<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>posts on Wanderer Demo Site</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/</link><description>Recent content in posts on Wanderer Demo Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>High Tatras</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/</guid><description>Embarking on a solo climbing adventure, I set my sights on the High Tatras, the smallest alpine mountain range in Europe, renowned for its rugged peaks and breathtaking landscapes. Armed with determination, climbing gear, and a deep respect for the mountains, I embarked on a journey that would test my limits and reward me with unforgettable experiences.
Day 1: Arrival and Acclimatization My adventure began in the charming town of Poprad, Slovakia, which serves as the gateway to the High Tatras.</description></item><item><title>Femundsmarka National Park</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/femundsmarka/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/femundsmarka/</guid><description>Femundsmarka National Park, located in the heart of Norway, is a pristine wilderness area that offers a true escape into nature. Renowned for its vast landscapes, serene lakes, and rich biodiversity, Femundsmarka is a haven for outdoor enthusiasts seeking adventure and tranquility. This article will guide you through the essential aspects of travelling to Femundsmarka, from the best time to visit to the activities you can enjoy in this breathtaking national park.</description></item></channel></rss>