<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Slovakia on Wanderer</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/trips/slovakia/</link><description>Recent content in Slovakia on Wanderer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/trips/slovakia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>High Tatras</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/</guid><description>&lt;p>Embarking on a solo climbing adventure, I set my sights on the High Tatras, the
smallest alpine mountain range in Europe, renowned for its rugged peaks and
breathtaking landscapes. Armed with determination, climbing gear, and a deep
respect for the mountains, I embarked on a journey that would test my limits
and reward me with unforgettable experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;a href="images/tatry.jpg">&lt;img src="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/images/tatry.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="day-1-arrival-and-acclimatization">Day 1: Arrival and Acclimatization&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My adventure began in the charming town of Poprad, Slovakia, which serves as
the gateway to the High Tatras. After a smooth flight and a short train ride, I
arrived in this picturesque town surrounded by towering peaks. I checked into a
cozy mountain lodge, unpacked my gear, and spent the afternoon exploring
Poprad. The blend of traditional Slovak architecture and modern amenities
provided a perfect setting to acclimatize.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smokovec</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/smokovec/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/smokovec/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nestled in the heart of Slovakia&amp;rsquo;s High Tatras, Starý Smokovec is a picturesque
mountain town that serves as a gateway to the Tatra National Park. Known for
its blend of historic charm and natural beauty, it&amp;rsquo;s an ideal destination for
both adventure seekers and those looking to unwind.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/smokovec/images/starysmokovec.jpg">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>One of the town&amp;rsquo;s highlights is the funicular railway to Hrebienok, offering
panoramic views of the surrounding peaks. From Hrebienok, visitors can access a
network of hiking trails leading to attractions like the Waterfalls of Studený
potok and Rainer&amp;rsquo;s Cottage, the oldest chalet in the High Tatras . For more
experienced hikers, the trail to Slavkovský štít provides a challenging ascent
with rewarding vistas.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>