<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Little Prince on Wanderer Demo Site</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/tags/little-prince/</link><description>Recent content in Little Prince on Wanderer Demo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/tags/little-prince/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter I</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter1/</guid><description>Once when I was six years old I saw a magnificent picture in a book, called True Stories from Nature, about the primeval forest. It was a picture of a boa constrictor in the act of swallowing an animal. Here is a copy of the drawing.
Boa In the book it said: &amp;ldquo;Boa constrictors swallow their prey whole, without chewing it. After that they are not able to move, and they sleep through the six months that they need for digestion.</description></item><item><title>Chapter II</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter2/</guid><description>So I lived my life alone, without anyone that I could really talk to, until I had an accident with my plane in the Desert of Sahara, six years ago. Something was broken in my engine. And as I had with me neither a mechanic nor any passengers, I set myself to attempt the difficult repairs all alone. It was a question of life or death for me: I had scarcely enough drinking water to last a week.</description></item><item><title>Chapter III</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter3/</guid><description>It took me a long time to learn where he came from. The little prince, who asked me so many questions, never seemed to hear the ones I asked him. It was from words dropped by chance that, little by little, everything was revealed to me.
The first time he saw my airplane, for instance (I shall not draw my airplane; that would be much too complicated for me), he asked me:</description></item><item><title>Chapter IV</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/chapter4/</guid><description>I had thus learned a second fact of great importance: this was that the planet the little prince came from was scarcely any larger than a house!
But that did not really surprise me much. I knew very well that in addition to the great planets&amp;ndash;such as the Earth, Jupiter, Mars, Venus&amp;ndash;to which we have given names, there are also hundreds of others, some of which are so small that one has a hard time seeing them through the telescope.</description></item></channel></rss>