<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hiking on Wanderer</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/categories/hiking/</link><description>Recent content in Hiking on Wanderer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:39:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/categories/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>High Tatras</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Embarking on a solo climbing adventure, I set my sights on the High Tatras, the
smallest alpine mountain range in Europe, renowned for its rugged peaks and
breathtaking landscapes. Armed with determination, climbing gear, and a deep
respect for the mountains, I embarked on a journey that would test my limits
and reward me with unforgettable experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href="images/tatry.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/high-tatras/images/tatry.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="day-1-arrival-and-acclimatization"&gt;Day 1: Arrival and Acclimatization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My adventure began in the charming town of Poprad, Slovakia, which serves as
the gateway to the High Tatras. After a smooth flight and a short train ride, I
arrived in this picturesque town surrounded by towering peaks. I checked into a
cozy mountain lodge, unpacked my gear, and spent the afternoon exploring
Poprad. The blend of traditional Slovak architecture and modern amenities
provided a perfect setting to acclimatize.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Femundsmarka National Park</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/femundsmarka/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/femundsmarka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Femundsmarka National Park, located in the heart of Norway, is a pristine
wilderness area that offers a true escape into nature. Renowned for its vast
landscapes, serene lakes, and rich biodiversity, Femundsmarka is a haven for
outdoor enthusiasts seeking adventure and tranquility. This article will guide
you through the essential aspects of travelling to Femundsmarka, from the best
time to visit to the activities you can enjoy in this breathtaking national
park.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Smokovec</title><link>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/smokovec/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/smokovec/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nestled in the heart of Slovakia&amp;rsquo;s High Tatras, Starý Smokovec is a picturesque
mountain town that serves as a gateway to the Tatra National Park. Known for
its blend of historic charm and natural beauty, it&amp;rsquo;s an ideal destination for
both adventure seekers and those looking to unwind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://mnezerka.github.io/wanderer/posts/smokovec/images/starysmokovec.jpg"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the town&amp;rsquo;s highlights is the funicular railway to Hrebienok, offering
panoramic views of the surrounding peaks. From Hrebienok, visitors can access a
network of hiking trails leading to attractions like the Waterfalls of Studený
potok and Rainer&amp;rsquo;s Cottage, the oldest chalet in the High Tatras . For more
experienced hikers, the trail to Slavkovský štít provides a challenging ascent
with rewarding vistas.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>